♪The journey is long, but fearless♪
♪路途遥远，但无所畏惧♪
♪Yeah soft attachment love♪
♪嗯柔软的依恋之爱♪
♪Scars will always heal♪
♪伤痕总会愈合♪
♪They will become flowers of time♪
♪它们会变成时光之花♪
♪Someone will give it to you♪
♪有人会给你♪
♪ Keep going! You won't be alone♪
♪继续前进！ 你不会孤单♪
♪Conversation with time♪
♪与时间对话♪
♪Light is your answer♪
♪光就是你的答案♪
♪I hope she is your future♪
♪我希望她是你的未来♪
♪Have tea, family, happiness♪
♪有茶有家人，幸福♪
♪There are always regrets in life♪
♪人生总有遗憾♪
♪But you still love♪
♪但你依然爱着♪
♪Father and winter♪
♪父亲和冬天♪
【Love is a panacea】 【Episode 8】
【爱情是灵丹妙药】 【第8集】
[Works funded by Sichuan Province Major Literary Project in 2022]
【 2022年四川省重大文学工程资助作品】
[Adapted from the Ningmeng language novel "Love is the Panacea"]
【改编自凝梦语言小说《爱情是灵丹妙药》 】
Su Wei'an already has it
苏危安已经有了
Have you had any illnesses before?
之前有什么病吗？
No.
不。
Where is her family?
她的家人呢？
Are there genetic diseases?
是否有遗传病
In her family?
在她的家人中？
No.
不。
Before going to college, Wei An and I
上大学之前，我和维安
We did a physical exam together.
我们一起做了体检。
She is in good health.
她身体健康。
His father died in a car accident.
他的父亲在车祸中去世。
Before his death, he ran a marathon every year
去世前，他 每年都跑马拉松
and enjoy good health.
并享有良好的健康状况。
Her mother participates in square dancing every day
她妈妈 每天都参加广场舞
It's also very healthy.
它也非常健康。
why do you ask?
你为什么要问？
anything.
任何事物。
Dr. Xu.
徐博士。
How is it going?
最近好吗？
Don't worry.
不用担心。
No damage to organs.
对器官没有损害。
only
仅有的
The wound was deep and there was a lot of blood loss.
伤口很深 ，失血过多。
I gave him 800 ml of blood transfusion.
我给他 输了800毫升的血。
She remains in a coma.
她仍处于昏迷状态。
She will be transferred to the infirmary for observation.
她将被转移 到医务室观察。
Can we go see her now?
我们现在可以去看她吗？
It's so late.
已经这么晚了。
Let her rest well.
让她好好休息。
There is a nurse on duty in the ward
病房有护士值班
Who will take good care of her.
谁会好好照顾她。
By the way, Dr. Xu,
顺便说一句，徐医生，
please do this
请这样做
Whole body CT scan
全身 CT 扫描
or MRI.
或核磁共振检查。
Also, check out your heart ultrasound,
同时，检查 你的心脏超声检查，
Blood routine , tumor markers, etc.
血常规 、肿瘤标志物等。
Give him a complete physical exam.
给他做一次全面的身体检查。
some problems?
一些问题？
Do you doubt my medical skills?
你怀疑 我的医术吗？
No.
不。
And one more thing
还有一件事
I need to confirm this.
我需要确认这一点。
OK
好的。
I will issue the medical examination documents.
我将签发 体检文件。
PhD. Gu.
博士。顾。
Why do you need to come to Wei'an for a physical examination?
为什么需要 来渭安体检？
You are with her every day.
你每天都和她在一起。
Has she been acting strangely lately?
她最近有什么奇怪的举动吗？
No.
不。
Doctor Gu, don't scare me.
顾医生，别吓我。
What happened to Wei An?
维安怎么了？
She is sick?
她生病了？
Hope not.
希望不是。
(I'm not dead yet.)
（我还没死。）
(I am saved.)
（我得救了。）
(I must live a good life.)
（我一定要好好生活。）
Sue, you wake up.
苏，你醒了。
how are you feeling?
你感觉怎么样？
much better.
好多了。
Thank you Dr. Xu.
谢谢徐医生。
Your superb medical skills saved my life again.
您精湛的医术 再次救了我的命。
You don't need to thank me.
你不需要感谢我。
Just thank you Dr. Gu.
就谢谢顾医生了。
He was very anxious when he saw something happened to you.
他看到你出事了，非常着急。
neurosurgeon
神经外科医生
They've seen it all.
他们已经看到了这一切。
Why was he so panicked when he saw blood?
为什么 一看到血，他就这么惊慌？
But he didn't come to see me.
但他没有来看我。
last night
昨夜
He waited until the operation was over
他一直等到 手术结束
It was good to see you before he comes back.
在他回来之前看到你很好。
Where is my bag?
我的包在哪里？
Have you seen my bag?
你看到我的包了吗？
What bag?
什么包？
My carry-on bag.
我随身携带的包。
All my stuff...
我所有的东西...
Do not move.
不要动。
You just had surgery.
你刚做完手术。
listen.
听。
This way the wound will open easily.
这样伤口 就会很容易打开。
I remember that lady Jiang
我记得那个小姐 蒋
I was holding that bag yesterday.
昨天我拿着那个袋子。
It won't be lost. Don't worry.
它不会丢失。不用担心。
Take a good rest first.
先好好休息吧。
Thanks.
谢谢。
(Su Weian’s test results were all normal.)
（苏伟安的检查结果 全部正常。）
(A hard copy will be sent to you this afternoon.)
（纸质版 将于下午发送给您。）
(What's up with her?)
（她怎么了？）
Cefinho.
切菲尼奥。
And Sirta. they are
还有斯尔塔。他们是
Sim.
西姆。
Cefinho.
切菲尼奥。
Did you hear me?
你听到我说话了吗？
And Sirta. they are
还有斯尔塔。他们是
He remembers.
他记得。
Don't you want to see her?
你不想见她吗？
The brain tumor patient we admitted yesterday
我们昨天收治的脑肿瘤患者
Surgery is expected tonight.
预计今晚进行手术。
Are you prepared before the surgery?
手术前你做好准备了吗？
Cefinho.
切菲尼奥。
miss. Sue is hurt
错过。苏很受伤
And a lot of blood was shed.
并流了很多血。
You were too anxious last night.
昨晚你太着急了。
Why do you act like nothing happened today?
你 今天怎么一副什么都没发生的样子？
I've thought about this.
我已经考虑过这个问题了。
She eventually committed suicide.
她最终自杀了。
I don't want to see her now.
我现在不想见她。
(Vian, have you ever thought about it)
（维安，你有没有想过）
(What should I do if you die?)
（如果你死了我该怎么办？）
River,
江，
I have good news for you.
我有好消息告诉你。
miss. Awakened.
错过。苏醒了。
What does this have to do with me?
这跟我有什么关系？
Aren't you best friends?
你们不是最好的朋友吗？
Why don't you take care of her?
你为什么不去照顾她呢？
I don't plan to.
我不打算。
She doesn't need anyone's attention.
她不需要 任何人的关注。
I have work to do. Don't block my way.
我有工作要做。 别挡我的路。
What's wrong?
怎么了？
【Friendship Hospital】
【友谊医院】
take this medicine
服此药
Twice a day.
每天两次。
that's it.
就这些。
Will Eastow of Vian.
威安的威尔·伊斯托。
Stop this.
停止这个。
Inside is Vivian's underwear.
里面是 薇安的内衣。
Why did you give them to me?
你为什么把它们给我？
I don't think it's appropriate for me to have them handed to me.
我认为我把它们交给我是不合适的。
Just give it to her!
就给她吧！
Cefinho.
切菲尼奥。
What a guy you are.
你真是个家伙。
You said you don't care, Miss Sue,
你说你不关心 小姐 苏，
So what are you doing here?
那么你在这里做什么？
lips
嘴唇
They are a bit dry.
它们有点干。
Prepare a box of cotton swabs.
准备一盒棉签。
Everything is there.
一切都在那里。
Are you awake?
你醒着么。
Because is you?
因为是你？
Some people say your lips are dry
有人说你的嘴唇 干燥
and ask
并询问
Let me rub them.
让我擦它们。
anyone there?
有人吗？
WHO？
WHO？
I can't say.
我不能说。
Gu Yunzheng?
Gu Yunzheng?
I can't help you think this way.
我无法帮助 你这样想。
That...
那...
all these are
这些都是
Your personal clothes.
你的个人衣服。
Don't get me wrong.
不要误解我。
I was asked to give them to you.
别人让我 把它们给你。
Someone else?
另一个人？
Jiang?
蒋？
I did not say anything.
我什么都没说。
Why these people who commissioned it
为什么这些 委托它的人
Won't you come to see me?
你不来看我吗？
This is because they are too busy working
这是因为他们 工作太忙
Or don't you want to see me?
还是你不想见我？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
get well soon.
早日康复。
and then
进而
Ask them yourself.
你自己去问他们。
in this case,
在这种情况下，
do something for them
为他们做点什么
for me.
为我。
Is anyone?
有人是吗？
Socorro!
索科罗！
Jiang, it’s me.
蒋，是我。
it's me.
是我。
Fang Mingfan!
Fang Mingfan!
Are you crazy?
你疯了？
Why did you break into the girls' dormitory in the middle of the night?
为什么半夜闯女生宿舍？
Do you want to scare me to death?
你想吓死我吗？
someone said
有人说
Who's afraid you'll forget to turn off the fan?
谁怕你忘记 关风扇
and let me take a look
并让我看一下
In case you catch a cold.
万一你感冒了。
anyone there?
有人吗？
WHO？
WHO？
Just one person.
只是一个人。
【Friendship Hospital】
【友谊医院】
Fang Mingfan!
Fang Mingfan!
What did you give me to drink?
你给我喝了什么？
What a dark thing.
多么黑的东西啊。
Is it mud?
是泥吗？
I know.
我知道。
This is a rare coffee bean from someone's private collection.
这是某人私人收藏 的稀有咖啡豆。
But I don't know how to grind coffee beans or brew coffee.
但我不知道如何研磨 咖啡豆或冲泡咖啡。
It's like being spoiled.
就好像被宠坏了一样。
You guys are so annoying.
你们真烦人。
Serving them is very difficult.
为他们服务是非常困难的。
I had to enter the service industry as a surgeon
我必须 以外科医生的身份进入服务行业
And keep your secrets.
并保守你的秘密。
It's too difficult for me.
对我来说太难了。
She may have had her stitches removed.
她可能 已经拆线了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Your career in the service industry
您在服务行业的职业生涯
It must end here.
它必须在这里结束。
Wei An's report will come to fruition as soon as possible.
维安的报告 尽快有了成果。
All indicators are normal.
各项指标均正常。
Not just normal,
不只是正常，
But she is healthier than me.
但她比我健康。
PhD. Gu.
博士。顾。
Take your medicine.
吃药吧。
How could you give me such medicine?
你怎么能给我 这样的药？
This is
这是
This is your medical report.
这是你的医疗报告。
Take a look.
看一看。
When did I have a physical exam?
我什么时候做过体检？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
I thought you had a terminal illness
我以为你得了 绝症
Do whatever it takes to die.
尽一切可能去死。
It seems I was wrong.
看来我错了。
You are very healthy.
你非常健康。
I saw your insurance policy.
我看到了你的保险单。
Everyone is doomed.
每个人都注定要死。
Or you can get 100,000 yuan in compensation,
或者可以获得十万 的赔偿，
Or you could receive a million.
或者你可以收到一百万。
I want to see how much I can get in return.
我想看看我能得到多少 回报。
You won't get a penny.
你不会得到一分钱。
Who said that?
谁说的？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
If you commit suicide like this again
如果你再这样自杀的话
I will definitely report it to the insurance company
我一定会向保险公司报告的
To cheat.
为了作弊。
I'll do what I'm told.
我会照我说的去做。
What is a lie?
什么骗什么？
also,
此外，
Who said I committed suicide?
谁说我自杀了？
But this is not helping others for righteous reasons.
但这并不是 出于正义的原因帮助他人。
You just want to die.
你只是想死。
Ever since you dropped out of school and came to Lacaha
自从你辍学 来到拉卡哈
until everything happened
直到发生的一切
Ever since I met him,
自从遇见他，
i finally realized
我终于意识到
what are you up to.
你要做什么。
Instead of watching you try to commit suicide every day,
而不是看着你每天试图自杀，
I make better use of my expertise
我更好地利用我的专业知识
Come and help her.
来帮助她。
what do you want to do?
你想让我做什么？
You just want to be euthanized .
你只想被安乐死 。
Now you no longer need to think about going to Switzerland.
现在您不再需要考虑 去瑞士。
The medicine I just gave you
我刚刚给你的药
Will make your wishes come true.
会让你的愿望 成真。
Wait for you...
等你...
it's no use.
这是没有用的。
It dissolves as soon as you take it.
你一服用它就会溶解。
Have I angered you?
我激怒你了吗？
this medicine
这个药
Made from resin mixture
由树脂混合物制成
dragon blood tree,
龙血树，
cactus sap,
仙人掌汁液，
Dahlia petals, fire lily stems and rooster's blood.
大丽花花瓣、火百合茎 和公鸡血。
it is used by wizards
它被巫师使用
Help terminally ill patients
帮助绝症患者
Free yourself from the pain of illness.
使自己摆脱 疾病的痛苦。
Just eat it
就吃它吧
You will die peacefully in your sleep,
你会 在睡梦中平静地死去，
without having the disease.
而不患有该疾病。
What a mystery.
多么神秘啊。
It's obviously witchcraft,
很明显这是巫术，
Not poison.
不是毒药。
It's not actually poison.
其实并不是毒药。
This is the medicine for happiness
这就是快乐的良药
This can help people who want to have euthanasia.
这可以帮助那些 想要实行安乐死的人。
you feel hot
你感觉很热
and a little
并有一点
Headquarters
总部的
Want to drink water?
想喝水吗？
It's working.
它正在发挥作用。
You're going to kill me.
你要杀死我了。
For a healthy person,
对于一个健康的人来说，
Drogamata
德罗加马塔
But for you,
但对你来说，
that's just
那只是
help.
帮助。
You must be lying to me.
你一定是在骗我。
I'm not telling lies.
我不是说假话。
Su Wei'an,
Su Wei'an,
idea
想法
You will die for me.
你会为我而死。
But now I understand.
但现在我明白了。
You can die anytime, anywhere ,
随时随地都可能死 ，
a strange child,
一个陌生的孩子，
Or anything.
或任何事情。
What's important
重要的是
You didn't do this for no reason
你这样做不是 无缘无故的
But he just wanted to die.
但他只是想死。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
after you die,
你死后，
I will dissect it
我将剖析它
I'll sell all your organs
我会卖掉你所有的器官
Not a black market.
不是黑市。
In view of our friendship,
鉴于我们的友谊，
I'll transfer all the money
我会把所有的钱转过去
To your mother.
给你妈妈。
OK
好的。
Anyway,
反正，
After I die, you will not be able to escape the punishment of the law.
我死后，你将无法逃脱法律的制裁。
So I'm giving up my life
所以我要放弃我的生命
For you.
为你。
Su Wei'an, what are you doing?
苏薇安你在做什么？
Don't do that!
不要那样做！
See you!
Deite se！
There are still six hours until the game.
距离比赛还有六个小时。
He listens to me.
他听我的。
The best thing about this medicine is,
这种药最好的一点 是，
After taking it,
服用后，
His organs will soon fail,
他的器官很快就会衰竭，
Unless you drink a lot of water now
除非你 现在喝很多水
To dilute toxins in the body.
以稀释体内毒素。
Don't you want to die?
你不想死吗？
say loudly
大声地说
You don't want to die.
你不想死。
explain!
说！
I don't want to die.
我不要死。
I want to live. all good?
我想生活。都好？
Why do you want to live?
你为什么想活下去？
tell me why.
告诉我为什么。
Once you tell me,
一旦你告诉我，
I'll give you water.
我会给你水。
I'll give you the antidote too.
我也给你解药。
An extra year of life is a victory.
多活一年就是胜利。
Wouldn't it be such a waste to die so quickly?
这么快就死了不是太浪费了吗？
And my mother is still waiting for me at home.
而妈妈还在 家里等我。
OK
好的。
I admit that I am afraid of death.
我承认我害怕死亡。
everything is fine?
一切安好？
Antidote.
解毒剂。
[iron-containing tablets]
[含铁片]
Iron sheets.
铁片。
Gu Yunzheng, is it so fun to lie to me?
顾云铮， 骗我有这么好玩吗？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
you haven't thought about it
你没有想过
What happens after you die?
你死后会发生什么？
you organized
你组织了
Your last words, bank card
你的遗言， 银行卡
And the insurance policy is clear.
和保险单明确。
but
但
what would you do
你会怎么办
if these are
如果这些是
The last six hours of your life?
你生命的最后六个小时？
that is not...
那不是...
No matter if,
无论是否，
I hope you remember what I said today.
我希望你记住 我今天说的话。
You don't want to die.
你不想死。
You want to live.
你想活下去。
I saved your life.
我救了你的命。
I hope to start from today
我希望从今天开始
You can take care of yourself.
你可以照顾好 自己。
Stop despising your life like this.
别再这样鄙视自己的生活了。
Bring an umbrella when it rains.
下雨的时候带把伞。
wear more clothes
多穿点衣服
When it's cold.
天冷的时候。
if you are sick,
如果你生病了，
I won't let her go.
我不会让她走的。
have a good rest.
好好休息。
Remember to take iron tablets.
记得服用 含铁药片。
You are anemic.
你贫血。
PhD. Gu.
博士。顾。
How about Vian?
维安怎么样？
I think she is very good.
我觉得她很好。
I hope
我希望
She actually listened to me.
她实际上在听我说话。
Jiang.
蒋.
You finally came to see me.
你终于来看我了。
I miss you.
我很想你。
Do you feel pain?
你感到疼痛吗？
There is a hole in my stomach.
我的肚子上有一个洞。
I need a beautiful woman to hold me.
我需要一个美女 来抱我。
you know what you told me
你知道你告诉我什么
That evening?
那天晚上？
European Union...
欧洲联盟...
Did I tell you my bank card password?
我有告诉你我的银行卡密码吗？
Can you forget her?
你能忘记她吗？
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
When we were still in school,
当我们还在学校的时候，
you told me,
你告诉我的，
Let’s go to Iceland together to see the Northern Lights in the future
以后我们一起去冰岛 看北极光
We will go to all the milk tea shops in Gimhae together.
我们会一起去 金海所有的奶茶店。
No matter who gets married first,
不管 谁先结婚，
We will be each other's bridesmaids
我们将成为彼此的伴娘
and godmother to the children.
和孩子们的教母。
When we get old,
当我们老了，
Let's retire together
我们一起退休吧
In a place facing the sea.
在一个面向大海的地方。
I take it seriously
我认真对待
Everything you said.
你所说的一切。
But what about you?
但你呢？
You arrived at Lakaha without saying a word.
你一言不发地来到了拉卡哈。
He went to the police station and was stabbed.
他去了警察局 ，结果被刺伤了。
He told me he was going to run away with Elliot.
他告诉我他要和艾略特私奔。
Jiang.
蒋.
hang on. Listen to me first.
不挂断。先听我说。
I just want to ask
我只是想问
If you consider my feelings
如果你考虑过我的感受
Before making a decision?
在做出决定之前？
You still consider me a friend
你还是把我当朋友
in your heart?
在你心里？
You feel
你觉得
what would i do
我会做什么
and
和
will you die?
你会死吗？
What do I say to your mother?
我要对你妈妈说什么？
Jiang.
蒋.
Really sorry.
真的对不起。
I know I'm stupid
我知道我很傻
it's useless,
没用的，
I'm with you every day,
我每天都陪伴着你，
There is absolutely nothing I can do.
我根本无能为力。
I am your burden.
我是你的负担。
Jiang.
蒋.
This is not true.
这不是真的。
He listens to me.
他听我的。
Parley, Vian.
帕雷，维安。
I made a decision.
我决定了。
I will buy a ticket and return to China in a few days.
过几天我就买票 回国。
We have all grown up.
我们都长大了。
I won't be attached to you anymore.
我不会再依附于你了。
River!
江！
【Friendship Hospital】
【友谊医院】
you know you are poisoned
你知道你中毒了
So you're afraid you won't wake up
所以你害怕你不会醒来
If not, are they?
如果不是的话，他们是吗？
I've been lying down for a long time
我已经躺了很长时间了
I want to breathe some air.
我想要呼吸一些空气。
let's go.
我们走吧。
I will go with you.
我和你一起去。
no need.
没有必要。
Things weren't that dramatic.
事情并没有那么戏剧化。
It’s not that I can’t walk.
并不是我不能走路。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I'll take you to a place.
我带你去一个地方。
where are we going?
我们去哪？
You will find out later.
稍后你就会知道。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
you know
你知道
What does a glioma specialist do?
神经胶质瘤专家做什么？
What does it mean for me?
对我来说意味着什么？
So you pushed me here in the middle of the night
所以你 半夜把我推到这里
just to show me
只是为了给我看
brilliant resume
辉煌的简历
The youngest associate professor of neurosurgery in the country?
全国最年轻的神经外科副教授？
majority of patients
大多数患者
I see gliomas every year
我每年都会看到神经胶质瘤
Whether you have malignant tumors
是否患有恶性肿瘤
in stages three and four.
在第三阶段和第四阶段。
your average survival rate
你的平均生存率
It's 15 to 17 months.
是15到17个月。
i saw the kids
我看到了孩子们
Those who are just starting to learn,
那些刚开始学习的人，
Students who are about to graduate from university,
即将 大学毕业的学生，
very talented painter
非常有才华的画家
and recently retired seniors
以及刚刚退休的老年人
And get ready to travel the world with your husband .
并准备好与你的丈夫一起环游 世界。
many of them
其中很多
very interesting.
非常有趣。
I really want to make friends with them
我很想和他们交朋友
But I don't dare.
但我不敢。
Because there's always a voice in the background
因为背景中总有一个声音
remind me
提醒我
They will leave this world soon .
他们很快就会离开 这个世界。
I remember
我记得
A couple's.
一对夫妇的。
husband
丈夫
Have glioblastoma.
患有胶质母细胞瘤。
Electric field treatment
电场处理
Nearly a million are spent each year.
每年花费近百万。
His wife sold the house
他的妻子卖掉了房子
Taking care of a sick husband alone
独自照顾生病的丈夫
and a son who is about to go to college .
和即将上大学的儿子 。
She is very strong
她特别坚强
and optimism.
和乐观。
There is also a mother,
还有一位母亲，
Its NMR results
其 核磁共振结果
showed a particularly poor prognosis.
表现出 特别差的预后。
She cried in the clinic,
她在诊所里哭了，
beg
乞求
i left her
我离开了她
Live a few more years.
多活几年。
she wants to teach
她想教书
your child is in kindergarten
你的孩子在幼儿园
Dress and eat alone.
独自穿衣吃饭。
Actually,
实际上，
There are many other examples
还有很多其他的例子
people like this
像这样的人
Those who refuse to surrender to death.
那些拒绝向死亡屈服的人。
No matter how critical the situation is,
无论 情况多么危急，
Some people never give up.
有些人永不放弃。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
I have no idea
我不知道
Why don't you take your life seriously?
你为什么不 认真对待你的生活呢？
I just want you to know
我只是想让你知道
who is surrounded by people
谁被人们包围
Who cares about you.
谁关心你。
Jiang Muying,
Jiang Muying,
your mother,
你的母亲，
And me.
和我。
your life
你的生命
it's really important
这真的很重要
For those who loved her.
对于那些爱她的人。
We don't know what will happen tomorrow.
我们不知道明天会发生什么。
But in times like now,
但像现在这样的时刻，
where you can admire the moon
在那里你可以赏月
And smell the flowers,
并闻花香，
It is so precious.
实在是太珍贵了。
I also want to live.
我也想活下去。
they are.
他们是。
Someone is looking for you.
有人正在找你。
Hello.
你好。
Thank you for saving my baby.
谢谢你救了我的宝宝。
you are lucky star
你是幸运星
And helped me get rid of bad luck.
并帮助我摆脱 了厄运。
She calls me her lucky star.
她称我为她的幸运星。
This is the first time anyone has said this to me.
这是第一次 有人对我说这样的话。
This is what we must do.
这是我们必须做的。
You're welcome.
不客气。
I will take you to see the rainbow in the dark night
我会带你去 见黑夜里的彩虹
Be blessed on the next full moon.
在下一个满月时受到祝福。
Is there a rainbow in the dark night?
黑夜里有彩虹吗？
tell me.
告诉我。
careful.
小心。
Isa just told me
伊萨刚刚告诉我
About local customs.
关于当地的习俗。
mothers with their children
妈妈们带着她们的孩子
Pray to the rainbow in the dark night
向黑夜中的彩虹 祈祷
Good luck with your child.
祝您的孩子好运。
The nearest place where you can see a rainbow in the dark night
黑夜里最近能看到彩虹的地方
Just in Labei Village.
就在拉北村。
Why are you looking at me?
你为什么看着我？
Is there money on my face?
我脸上有钱吗？
Labei Village is far away.
拉北村很远。
If you pick up my car, I'll give you a 20% discount
如果你提我的车，我会给你 20% 的折扣
You're still thinking about business.
你还在想着生意。
It seems
看起来
You can live well.
你可以生活得很好。
do you want to accompany me
你想陪我吗
Watching a rainbow at night?
晚上看彩虹？
Clear.
清除。
So it was agreed upon.
所以就这么约定了。
Jiang.
蒋.
do not go.
不要去。
Sit down and eat. I am so hungry.
坐下来吃饭。 我饿死了。
Come.
来。
Feel.
感觉。
Jiang, look.
蒋，你看。
This is your favorite.
这是你最喜欢的。
The supply of Lacaha is limited.
拉卡哈的供应有限。
I bought everything I could.
我买了所有我能买的东西。
try it.
尝试一下。
Let’s start with tripe.
我们先从牛肚开始吧。
We've ordered tripe before
我们以前点过牛肚
When we ordered the red oil hotpot.
当我们点 红油火锅的时候。
You love it.
你喜欢它。
Cook the tripe seven times upwards and eight times downwards.
将牛肚向上煮七次 ，向下煮八次。
The longer it goes, the more difficult it becomes.
时间越长， 难度就越大。
It is difficult to chew and tastes bad.
很难咀嚼 ，味道也会变差。
Better to throw it away.
最好把它扔掉。
I'll eat it myself
我自己来吃吧
Let's cook the meat slices.
我们来煮肉片吧。
They won't be overcooked.
它们不会煮过头。
sauce.
酱汁。
This is the sauce I made just for you.
这是我专门为你做的酱汁。
they do not. You are the only one who has it.
他们没有。 你是唯一拥有它的人。
try it. This is delicious.
尝试一下。这很美味。
Red oil soup is very complicated.
红油汤 就很复杂了。
Use only pure sesame oil and minced garlic
仅使用纯芝麻油 和蒜泥
sauce.
酱汁。
Wouldn't it be nice to keep things simple?
让事情变得简单不是很好吗？
I am going to eat.
我要吃了。
I like the red oil soup with sesame sauce.
我喜欢加芝麻酱的红油汤。
Let's eat brown sugar mochi.
我们来吃 红糖麻糬吧。
Although mochi
虽然麻糬
La Caja can be found everywhere,
La Caja随处可见，
Brown sugar is hard to come by.
红糖很难买到。
Eat it while it's hot.
趁热吃吧。
brown sugar mochi,
红糖麻糬，
It's sweet and sickly.
它又甜又病态。
If you eat too much, it will be difficult to digest
吃太多的话 会很难消化
You won't be able to get rid of it.
你将无法摆脱它。
Let's drink Coca-Cola.
我们来喝可口可乐吧。
Give me Coca-Cola.
给我可口可乐。
Coca-Cola and hotpot go well together, just like us.
可口可乐和火锅很相配， 就像我们一样。
The bubbles of Coca-Cola add to the pain of spice.
可口可乐的气泡 增加了香料的痛苦。
They don't get along at all.
他们根本相处不好。
Jiang Muying.
Jiang Muying.
unacceptable.
太过分了。
Su Wei'an was injured.
苏危安受伤了。
But still prepared
但还是做好了准备
Your favorite food.
你最喜欢的食物。
Why did you suddenly change?
你怎么突然就变了？
Everyone changes.
每个人都会改变。
correct?
正确的？
Jiang, don't say that.
蒋，别这么说。
Sorry, I know
对不起，我知道
I made her angry.
我让她生气了。
Jiang.
蒋.
You came to Lacaha
你来到了拉卡哈
Have a great holiday.
度过一个愉快的假期。
Don't let me affect your mood.
别让我影响你的心情。
I know
我知道
I am reckless and impulsive
我鲁莽且冲动
And I always ignore your feelings.
而且我总是 忽视你的感受。
burden
负担
It must be me,
一定是我，
That can't be you!
那不可能是你！
if you really want to go
如果你真的想去的话
I dare not keep it.
我不敢保留它。
But I just want to tell you
但我只想告诉你
you are my best friend,
你是我最好的朋友，
Always has been and always will be.
一直如此，也永远如此。
This will never change.
这永远不会改变。
Don't be angry, okay?
别生气，好吗？
You are still recovering,
你还在康复中，
You can't eat spicy food.
你不能吃辛辣的食物。
OK
好的。
I will not eat.
我不吃。
I would eat it with a light soup.
我会配着清淡的汤吃。
I'm glad you're not angry anymore.
我很高兴 你不再生气了。
Cefinho.
切菲尼奥。
You ate all the good stuff
你吃掉了 所有好吃的东西
when we speak.
当我们说话时。
Nothing better than hotpot
没有什么比火锅更好的了
Can't be solved.
无法解决。
If there is,
如果有，
Then eat twice.
然后吃两次。
correct.
正确的。
eat more.
多吃一点。
It's good for you.
对你有好处。
How to get duck tripe and duck intestines
如何获得鸭肚和鸭肠
In Lacaha?
在拉卡哈？
Thanks to the cafeteria aunt.
感谢食堂阿姨。
She also ordered two flavors of hot pot.
她还点了 两种口味的火锅。
Come, eat this.
来，吃这个。
To you too.
也给你。
[Be virtuous, good at art] Be virtuous.
【有德，善艺】 有德。
Good skills.
良好的技能。
Then,
然后，
How are you now?
你现在身体好吗？
I sincerely thank you.
我真诚地感谢你。
Why are you being sarcastic?
你为什么要讽刺？
Am I the only one who has this song?
我是唯一一个有这首歌的人吗？
Clear.
清除。
Dr. Xu performed the surgery on you.
徐医生给你做了手术。
How would you thank him?
你会怎样感谢他呢？
I promised to translate two documents for him.
我答应为他翻译两份文件。
What's this?
这是什么？
So I'm the only one
所以我是唯一一个
with this track.
与这首曲目。
You accepted it.
你接受了。
So shouldn't you do something for me?
那么你不应该为我做点什么吗？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Your bargaining personality
你讨价还价的个性
until the last penny
直到最后一分钱
It's written in your DNA.
它写在你的 DNA 里。
I want to ask Dr. Gu
我想请问顾医生
Come stay with me today.
今天来陪我。
You're welcome.
不客气。
I don't plan to.
我不打算。
I'm going to have surgery later.
我稍后要做手术。
But I've seen the timeline.
但我已经看到了时间表。
from now on,
今后，
You will no longer have outpatient visits or surgeries.
您将不再有门诊 或手术。
PhD. Gu.
博士。顾。
It has to be you.
一定得是你。
Why just me?
为什么只有我？
it can't be
它不可能是
Someone else?
另一个人？
Because you are not someone else.
因为你不是别人。
So I'll think about it.
所以我会考虑一下。
Once a teacher, always a father.
一日为师，终身为父。
You are my half-father.
你是我同父异母的父亲。
group?
派？
I don't plan to.
我不打算。
Then I'll notify everyone in the hospital
然后我会通知 医院里的所有人
Think Chinese doctors don’t care about human life,
认为中国医生不关心 人的生命，
Ignore the needs of patients ,
忽视患者的需求 ，
Ignoring the commonality of the Chinese people
无视中国人民的共同性
This is callous and inhumane.
这是冷酷且不人道的。
all good.
都好。
as you wish.
如你所愿。
I do not mind.
我不介意。
Let's leave it at that.
我们就到此为止吧。
careful!
小心！
Let's buy a mobile phone here.
我们在这里买手机吧。
[Cheap mobile phone store]
[廉价手机店]
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
I think I owed you something from my previous life.
我想我 上辈子欠你的。
Not in the previous life,
前世没有，
But last time.
但上次。
last time,
上次，
You threw my phone to the drug dealer
你把我的手机扔给了 毒贩
Without hesitation.
毫不犹豫。
It's an emergency.
这是紧急情况。
Emergency situations?
紧急情况？
Then why don't you throw away your phone ?
那你为什么不扔掉 自己的手机
Play with me?
玩我的？
How could the general's men who beat me find us?
打我的， 将军的人怎么会发现我们？
Are you the one called General's subordinate?
你就是那个叫 将军部下的人吗？
what do you think?
你怎么认为？
Did they come down from heaven?
他们是从天上下来的吗？
When you run out and drive your motorcycle,
当你跑出去 开摩托车时，
I sent a message to Jiang Muying
我给江暮影发消息了
and shared the location of the phone.
并分享了手机位置。
[Gu Yunzheng: Go find General Kuat. 】
【顾云正：去找 库阿特将军。】
[Gu Yunzheng is sharing the location. Come and join us. ]
【顾云正正在分享 位置。快来加入吧。]
[Share location between 2 people]
[2人共享位置]
What a man of plans!
多么有计划的人啊！
Multiple sclerosis. Su, take a closer look
多发性硬化症。苏你仔细看看
La Caja has no cell phone service.
La Caja 没有手机业务。
Maybe you can discover new business opportunities.
也许您可以发现 新的商机。
Make your choice.
做出你的选择。
I'll pay for whatever you want.
你想要什么我都会付钱。
great!
伟大的！
gentlemen!
先生！
I want the most expensive, newest phone.
我想要 最贵、最新的手机。
correct.
正确的。
This is the latest model.
这是最新型号。
what do you think?
你怎么认为？
Take a look.
看一看。
Is this the latest model?
这是最新型号吗？
Sim.
西姆。
I have never heard of this brand of cell phone.
我从来没有听说 过这个牌子的手机。
I want the most expensive one
我想要最贵的那一款
Sim.
西姆。
another.
另一个。
[TECN WT2]
[TECN WT2]
This is more expensive.
这个比较贵。
Fortunately.
幸运的是。
how much does it cost?
它要多少钱？
$280.
280 美元。
Very cheap.
很便宜。
It’s just over 1,000 yuan.
也就1000多块钱而已。
Is there anything more expensive?
还有更贵的吗？
Not in a hurry.
不着急。
Take it easy
慢慢来
and select until you like it.
并选择直到您喜欢为止。
I'll pay for it anyway .
无论如何我都会付钱的 。
Not in a hurry.
不着急。
you already know
你已经知道了
Doesn’t this store have any expensive mobile phones?
这家店没有很贵的手机吗？
how could I know?
我怎么知道？
You chose this store.
你选择了这家店。
Nothing you like?
没有什么你喜欢的吗？
This is good.
这很好。
let's see.
让我们来看看。
Thanks.
谢谢。
This is
这是
There are four cards and four patterns,
有四张牌和四种图案，
And has a tanning function.
并带有 晒黑功能。
The ringtone volume is quite loud.
铃声音量相当大。
I've seen patients use it.
我见过病人用它。
If it's good I can keep it.
如果它好的话我可以保留它。
Give me my old phone back.
把我的旧手机还给我。
OK
好的。
You don't like it?
你不喜欢？
So we won't buy it.
所以我们不会买。
No one is looking for you anyway
反正没人找你
wait!
等待！
Either way, it's free.
不管怎样，它都是免费的。
Then,
然后，
He paid.
他结账了。
Sim.
西姆。
How much?
多少钱？
$280.
280 美元。
Your boyfriend is so nice.
你男朋友真是太好了。
No, he is not my boyfriend.
不，他不是我男朋友。
♪Darkness makes the hour hand vibrate♪
♪黑暗使时针振动♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹渐渐取代了 寂静♪
♪We represent the itinerary of our meeting ♪
♪我们代表我们会议的行程 ♪
♪Embellished with rainbows at night♪
♪镶嵌着夜晚的彩虹♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪They are all our witnesses♪
♪他们都是我们的见证人♪
♪Who hasn’t experienced a reason for failure? ♪
♪谁没有经历过失败的原因？♪
♪Looking for the one in a billion possibility♪
♪寻找 十亿分之一的可能性♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny♪
♪被困在名为命运的都市♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪但还是追星♪
♪Don’t worry, I love lost people♪
♪别担心，我喜欢迷失的人♪
♪Raise the wine to warm the lonely soul♪
♪举起酒 来温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Please allow me to hug your slit♪
♪请允许我拥抱你的缝隙♪
♪You are as bright as a star♪
♪你像星星一样明亮♪
♪Shine in melancholy moments♪
♪在忧郁的时刻闪耀♪
♪Darkness makes the hour hand vibrate♪
♪黑暗使时针振动♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹渐渐取代了 寂静♪
♪We represent the itinerary of our meeting ♪
♪我们代表我们会议的行程 ♪
♪Embellished with rainbows at night♪
♪镶嵌着夜晚的彩虹♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪They are all our witnesses♪
♪他们都是我们的见证人♪
♪Who hasn’t experienced a reason for failure? ♪
♪谁没有经历过失败的原因？♪
♪Looking for the one in a billion possibility♪
♪寻找 十亿分之一的可能性♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny♪
♪被困在名为命运的都市♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪但还是追星♪
♪Don’t worry, I love lost people♪
♪别担心，我喜欢迷失的人♪
♪Raise the wine to warm the lonely soul♪
♪举起酒 来温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Please allow me to hug your slit♪
♪请允许我拥抱你的缝隙♪
♪You are as bright as a star♪
♪你像星星一样明亮♪
♪Shine in melancholy moments♪
♪在忧郁的时刻闪耀♪